HTML- 9th Jan

Topic: Git-branch

Merge conflict -> it arise when two separate branches have made some changes in the same line in a file. It mainly happen when working in team environment.

git remote -v  -> list of bookmarked repository name and the corresponding repository URL

git branch “branch_name” -> to create new branch

git branch -> show the branches that are in the git repository

git checkout new-branch -> help to switch with the branch

git checkout -b “new_branch_name” -> it create new branch and also switch it to the just created new branch. (Recommend to use this)

 git branch -d “branch_name” -> To delete the branch

How to merge the auth branch code to the main branch?
-> 1st go to main branch
-> git merge “merge_branch_name”

.gitignore -> tells git which files to ignore when commiting your project to the github repository.

Remember: you need to first specify the file inside .gitignore file with the file name after that  you have to create the file. If not it will track the file.

To learn more about .gitignore -> https://www.bmc.com/blogs/gitignore/




